Guide to the Pittsburgh Council, American Youth Hostel Records, 1955-2002 AIS.2004.20
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence, II.
  - Legal/Construction Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Allentown Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - SPERT Correspondence, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Finance Correspondence, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Environmental Correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 13, Folder 31)
- Activities, III.
  This series relates to projects and activities of which the Pittsburgh Council organized or were affiliated. These events include hiking trips at various local trails and bicycle rides (most pertain to the Great Ride, Mon Valley Century rides, and the Sabre ride). Also contained in this section is the extensive deliberation that occurred in the search for the placement of the hostel, which eventually settled in the Allentown section of Pittsburgh. Along with this project are documents detailing architectural decisions faced by the board.
  - Community Events (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Future Programming (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Activities Leadership (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Girl Scout Patch (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "Next Ten Years" Hostel Development Plans (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Nantucket Youth Hostel (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Sustainable Living (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Volunteer Works (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Volunteer Information (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Travel Evaluations (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Conservation Trail Directory (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - AYH Highway Sign (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Gettysburg Trips, 1986-1990 (Box 14, Folder 13-14)
  - Tudi Mechanical Services (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Architectural Assessments, Drawings, Contracts, 1996-1997 (Box 14, Folder 16-18)
  - Allentown Construction, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Construction Charge Plans, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Allentown Project Articles, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Sources for Food, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Flynn Contract Management (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - AYH Song Sheet (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Canoe Guides (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Eastern Western Regional Meeting Plans, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Cooper's Rock (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - April Board Retreat, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Donations (Box 14, Folder 29-30)
  - Salvation Army Building Costs, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Armstrong County Activity, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Bloomfield/Garfield Hostel Pitch (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Ohiopyle Misc. Projects and Activities, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Ohiopyle Railroad/Melwood (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Erie Hostel (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Olympic Bike Ride, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Cycling Events Information (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Whitewater Canoe School, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - AYH Clubs (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Blackwater Falls/Wilderness Lodge Information (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Sea Kayaking Program (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Cross-Country Skiing (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Canoeing Trip Information, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Outreach and Interpretive Programming, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - General Trip Management Guides (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - AYH Picnic and Awards Banquet Information (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - AYH Guidelines for Trip Leaders (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Permit and Trail Construction, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - AYH Sponsorship: Boy Scout Explorer (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Conservancy Trip and Hiking Guides (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - White Rocks Outing, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - Pennsylvania Trail Guide Information, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - Activity Membership Information, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Baker's Trail, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Trips and Trails, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Baker's Trail, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Extended Trips Program, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 04-05)
  - Cycle Planning, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Cycle Planning (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Great Ride, 1985-1989 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Liberty Ride Festival, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Kodak Liberty Ride, 1985-1989 (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
  - Fiscal Year: Ohiopyle, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Great Ride, 1989-1991 (Box 15, Folder 13-15)
  - Revised Charter and By-Laws, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Great Ride, 1992-1998 (Box 15, Folder 17-23)
  - Mon-Valley Century Bike Ride, 1994-1997 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Volunteer Information: Great Ride, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Thrift Drug Classic, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Cycling Special Events (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Monroeville Triathlon, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Misc. Rides/Activities and Finances, 1988-1993 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Misc. Riding Activity, 1988-1994 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - SABRE Bicycle Tour, 1994-1996 (Box 15, Folder 31-32)
  - Comparison Reports, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - 20 Mile Ride, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Bike Ride Articles, Copied (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Allentown Facility Renewal, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Mon-Valley Bike Ride Articles, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Headquarters Renovation, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Monthly Reports, June 1997 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Annual Council Agreements, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Mon-Valley Century, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - July Hip Report, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - PIH Reports, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Monthly Reports, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 08-11)
  - Floorplans and Safety Procedure, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Monthly Summaries, 1997-1999 (Box 16, Folder 13-37)
  - Annual Report Council, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Monthly Reports, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 39-41)
  - February Monthly Report, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - March Monthly Report, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Fiscal Year Budget, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Grant Correspondence, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 43)